# **QUENTIN DUBOURG**

Data scientist | Machine Learning & analyst +33 7 81 24 82 04

quentin.dubourgdeluzencon@gmail.com

- O vasydewey
- math quentin.dubourgdeluzencon.github.io

I pursue a career as as an engineer, I utilize **computer science & Machine Learning** to address challenges.

I have experience handling different parts of business data management, from storing it to interpreting it.

I am able to deliver a **complete project** from proof of concept to production.

# **SKILLS**

Machine Learning | Python | SQL | NoSQL | R | JavaScript | HTML | CSS| Git | CI/CD | Image processing | Deep learning NLP | Cloud computing | Graphic design | Web development | UX & UI design | Game development | Blender

### **EXPERIENCE**

Data manager 05/2022 - 10/2023

Borneo - French food delivery platform

I joined Borneo shortly after its creation and took charge of organizing and structuring all the customer data within the company. My primary focus was to ensure that this valuable information was easily accessible to internal departments and clients (±100 restaurants).

- I **structured customer data** for easy access by internal departments and clients. (noSQL, Firebase realtime database, BigQuery, Metabase, Python)
- I developed Dashboards (Metabase) to monitor operations, ensuringinformed real-time decision-making.
- I participated in the web design for the website and mobile apps. (UI & UX design, user path analysis)

Data scientist 06/2020 - 05/2022

Winamax - Online gambling and betting company

In order to meet the demands of different teams within the company, Winamaxhired me to establish a customer data analysis team that operates with adatabase of approximately 10 million users.

- I developed a **gambling addiction detection algorithm**, providing monthly reports to the french gambling authority. (XG Boost)
- Our team used **ML to manage CRM campaigns** (±10 millions users). (Dash plotly hosted on AWS, segmentations, predictions, A/B testing).
- · Macro-simulation of games to estimate the impact of new games on the platform.

## Data engineer junior

06/2020 - 05/2022

Ekimetrics - Data consulting

- I migrated customer data and ETL into **Azure Cloud** for an automotive company.
- I deployed pipelines (ETL) to classify customers and generate weekly leads.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Engineering degree (Master)**

2016 - 2019

Telecom Paris IPP & Eurecom

Major in mathematics and computer science. Specialization in Data Science, Machine Learning, Image processing. Semester exchange with Polytechnique Montréal (Québec).